Captioning made possible by
Warner Bros., inc.
The waves of winter--
mother nature
has cast her spell.
Waves to remember...
Calling us home.
Woo-hoo!
Serious?
Very.
Ready...
Set...
Go!
Woo-hoo!
Woo! yeah!
Yahoo!
* ...The midwest
farmers' daughters *
* really make you
feel all right *
* and the northern girls
with the way they kiss-- *
that's
a great song.
Same time
manana, brophy.
Unless I die
tonight, gook.
* well, the east coast
girls are hip... **
[television]
...the ninth.
98, 89.
You guys were
awesome today. Gracias.
[Barking]
Oh, slash!
What you been doing?
Chasing cats,
dreaming about t-bone?
That-a boy.
Come on.
This is
the first time
he's
old enough.
Hey, mom.
Hey, dad.
How were the waves
today, Mitchell?
breaking today?
All right.
What is it?
Who died?
Come on in here, honey.
Sit with us.
Sit with you.
Look,
don't be gentle.
Break it to me fast.
Sit down,
Mitchell.
That's the look
you had
when you put
strummer to sleep.
No.
not the slash dog.
O.k. tell me.
Your father and i
have been awarded a Grant.
The national
zoological
institute
has asked us
to study
the Australian
wombat.
Australia?
What are
you talking about?
That's great news!
We've never been
to Australia before!
I mean, I'm talking about
waves of seismic proportions,
summers that never quit,
and golden-tanned
sheilas.
This is incredible!
So when
do we leave?
We'd love
for you to go.
But it's
for six months.
You can't be out
of school that long.
Yes, I can.
No, you can't.
There'll be
other times,
but not during
the school year.
If I'm
not going...
That's just it,
Mitchell.
We've got
a surprise
for you.
Tell him
what it is,
Kate.
You get to stay
with your uncle Louie
and aunt Irene in Cincinnati!
They have a boy
your age--
cousin wiley.
They've been dying
to see you.
It's only
for six months.
It will be
good for you--
an education,
a chance to see how
other people live.
It'll be fun,
honey.
Look at it
as an adventure.
* what god wants *
* god gets *
* what god wants... **
[woman]
hi! yoo-hoo!
Come on, pa.
Yoo-hoo!
here we are!
Ha ha ha!
Here, father.
You take it.
Oh, is this
my Mitchell?
You're just
too grown up!
Give me
a big hug.
A big hug!
Yes! oh!
Welcome
to Cincinnati,
young fella, yeah.
Thanks
for having me.
Oh, isn't
he adorable?
These eyes are
like his mother's.
And this hair.
This hair!
My goodness!
Have you ever seen
such hair?
A fine piece
of hair.
How was
your trip?
Did you get
a window seat?
Stop the interrogating,
father.
Wiley, where are you?
Meet your cousin Mitchell.
The last time
that you saw each other,
you were both
in diapers.
He's so excited
to see you.
Mitchell, wiley.
Wiley,
your cousin Mitchell.
Woo!
How's it going,
man?
Nice
to meet you.
Likewise,
brah.
Brah.
[Louie]
yeah, well.
Ha ha!
Let's get on home.
We have catching up
to do.
Not
too many places
around here
to use that,
son.
I don't go anywhere
without my stick.
Without it,
I'm naked.
O.k. well...
Yeah, yeah.
Did you ever meet
that John Wayne in California?
No.
Father does
a good John Wayne.
Say "wagons ho!"
Come on.
Ha ha ha!
Well, anyway...
[As John wayne]
Put the wagon trains
in a circle!
We're so excited!
Slow down
a little, wiley.
Hands on 10 and 2.
He just got
his learner's permit.
Isn't that something
about your folks
going to Australia?
It's something,
all right.
You're
a handsome young man.
I bet all the young ladies
are after you.
You could give pointers
to my wiley here.
He's never had
a girlfriend.
Ma!
do you mind?
There's the big hole
where
the sausage factory was.
I'd like to go
to California sometime,
but I get dyspeptic
if I eat
too many salads.
Oh, wiley! Watch it!
Ha ha!
Home again,
home again.
[Irene]
...she's such
a character.
She puts a fur hat
on him when he goes out.
He's already got
a fur hat.
Wiley, take Mitchell
and show him his room.
I know you want to
rest before dinner.
I have prepared
in your honor
a very great feast.
You didn't have to
do that.
No! I wanted to!
You don't have to go
through all this trouble.
A nice creamed corn
surprise!
These boys
have lots in common.
That Mitchell
is tall.
Come on.
Whoa!
Got
any hockey on?
Watch
the, uh, way.
Come on.
Come on, come on!
All right.
Come on in.
Right here.
Come on,
come on.
O.k., you ready?
Ready?
Hit it.
Oh...
What do
you think, huh?
What
do you think?
It's wild,
right?
A wild man's room
in a wild man's city.
Thanks, man.
This is your bed
right here,
and, uh...
[Whistles]
She's something,
huh?
Your ma
would like her.
Don't let
the old lady
snow you, man.
This guy's been
around the block.
You catch my drift?
You picking up
what I'm putting
down?
I'm with you.
Cool, cool.
Hey! so,
you surf, huh?
Uh-huh.
That's cool.
Must be kind of
zenlike.
I guess it's
hard for you
to be
in Cincinnati.
Yeah.
I hope it won't be
too painful for you.
Hey, wiley,
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean it
that way.
We might just
have ourselves
some good times.
Think so?
You take the waves
with you, right?
Cincinnati's
a party town.
If anybody
can show you
a good time...
The wiley-man can.
Ha!
You'll like
the people here.
They're very easy
to make friends with.
[Bell rings]
Don't want to
be late.
Wiley.
Oh! what's
the rush?
Oh!
Whoa. watch it
there, my man.
O.k. come here.
What's wrong
with you?
That was snake,
man,
voted most likely
to eat his young.
You better
watch your step.
He might not
be so nice
next time.
All right.
Come on.
Just
follow my lead,
everything
will be cool,
all right?
Whatever
you say, man.
All right.
Good morning, class.
Good morning, Mr. cauley.
This is
my cousin Mitchell.
He's from California.
Good morning,
gentlemen.
Here you go.
He's going to
file your name
and stuff.
How's it going,
guys?
[Groaning]
Peace, brother.
Peace!
[Cauley]
we're pleased
to meet you.
Welcome
to central high,
and welcome
to speech class.
Find yourself
a seat.
We're just
getting ready
to introduce
ourselves.
Thank you,
Alexis.
Allow me.
Jackie-Jack.
A real
live gentleman.
Who would
have thought?
Whoa!
So, who wants to
be first?
Come up here.
Tell us
about yourself.
Do you use
a pump or a squeeze?
Anything at all.
Thank you, Molly.
Molly Ryan's my name.
I have a 3.8 gpa.
I'm the treasurer
of amnesty international,
and some day, I will be
a very successful attorney.
Next.
My name is snake.
I don't like speech.
I never even
signed up for it.
I ain't got no hobbies,
unless you call
collecting knives
and putting tattoos
on guys I don't like hobbies.
And I have a 1.1 gpa.
I refuse to starve myself
so some macho man
will think my tush
looks cute in tight jeans.
Someday, the jimbo...
Will be
a sports announcer.
Ha ha ha!
You watch.
I want to be
al Pacino's love slave.
Jose Augusto Rafael
de la parra.
Everyone just calls me
augie, though.
Uh, I really like, um...
To sleep,
and I like Nintendo.
I like Nintendo,
and I li--
and, uh...
[Snoring]
O.k. thank you,
rosenblat.
That's fine.
[Boys]
rosenblat! rosenblat!
Rosenblat! Rosenblat!
You all know me.
I'm the wiley-man.
Who?
Wiley metzner.
You know me.
We've talked.
We pass each other
in the halls.
You beat me up,
but I forgive you.
Anyway...
If you want to know
who wiley metzner is,
I'm a hockey man.
I live to play hockey.
I play hockey to live.
Yeah.
that's all I do.
I've got on hockey underwear
right now.
I have
a hockey toothbrush.
My dad
drives a zamboni.
He gave me a puck.
Psycho puck.
[Belch]
Ha ha!
What about
the new kid,
Mr. cauley?
Yeah.
it's his turn.
O.k., Mitchell.
[Girl]
oh, my heart.
Mitchell goosen
at your service.
I'm not
from around here.
I don't know what
i want to be when I grow up.
Don't care,
as long as
i live near the beach.
Then, I'll be stylin'.
Stylin'? what?
Let me tell you
what stylin' is.
The perfect session.
A-frame wave,
ground swell.
Spitting out saltwater
in your face,
doing a little
lip action move,
a 360
without a bounce.
I call it
a liquid drano,
wannabe bullwinkle.
I tell no lie.
It's a consciousness raiser.
Oh, man. I'm
going to throw up.
What's consciousness?
I don't know.
Give me some
captain crunch berries,
a couple bean burritos,
maybe an otter pop,
and I'm happy.
Could I add
something, please?
Uh, I think that
the pretty boy
maharishi over here
has been mixing
a little bit of drano
with his fruit punch.
You tell him,
augie!
Does anyone here
believe this L.A.,
laid-back...
Horse poo?
This guy is peddling.
I don't buy it.
You big,
fruity two-shoe.
Ha ha ha!
The old heinie hairs
are wound too tight.
What'd you say?
I just said
what a fine public speaker
augie was.
Yeah. I bet
you did.
Pretty boy...
Surfer.
All right, Jack.
You're next.
[Jack]
you, uh...
You don't
really think
surfing is
a sport, do you?
Ha ha!
It's not. Mm-mm.
It's badminton, man.
It's checkers.
It's getting
a suntan.
You want to try
a real sport?
Why don't you
try hockey?
As a matter
of fact, man,
we got a game today
against the preps.
That's right!
Against the preps!
We've never
beaten the preps,
and I'm not graduating
in may a loser.
We're nobody's doormat.
We're going to
do it today.
We'll kick
the preps' butt.
Yeah!yeah!
Let's hear it
for rosenblat!
Yeah!
[Bell rings]
Yeah.
good luck, man.
Don't
mess around.
[Cauley]
good first day.
Thanks for
your cooperation.
Going
to the game?
Never been
to a hockey game.
You'd love it,
man.
It's so cool.
So, what about you,
maharashi?
You coming
to the game?
Chill, brah.
Let it go, man.
Did he
just call you
a piece
of underwear?
Hey, Mitchell...
You just make friends
wherever you go?
Do what?
Seeing how many people
you can piss off?
Gandhi said,
"make waves,
not war."
Hi, Mitchell.
Como estan, ladies?
We wanted
to welcome you
to Cincinnati.
Uh,
Stan, ladies.
I'm wiley.
We're cousins.
[Simultaneously]
if there's anything you need...
Just
let me know.Us know.
Thank you
very much.
Hey, surfer boy.
Be careful.
That's Jack's
girlfriend.
We were just showing
Mitchell some hospitality.
Hi. you are
so sweet.
Guess what,
moondoggie?
Cute little earring.
I'll do everybody
a big favor,
save a little time,
and kick
your little butt now.
Don't mess around
with other people's
property.
Chill, brah.
He did it again.
I'm going to
kill him.
Jack, guess what!
Pico and Freddie
got caught--
putting ex-lax
in Mrs. kroen's
coffee.
They'll
get detention.
Count them out
for the game.
We'll get somebody.
The figure skating
squad?
How about
the mixed pairs
team?
Hey, I'll play.
All right.
All right, man.
You're in. Cool.
We're still
a man short,
'cause...
You.
Me?
Yes.
Where do i
know you from?
You used to
flush my head
in the urinals.
Willy.
Wiley.
Whatever.
You're playing
hockey today.
Uh...great!
Mmm...
Tuesday, right?
I can't.
Dentist appointment.
I was chewing
on a cashew
and, uh,
exposed a root.
You're playing.
No. you know--
ow! No.
You're playing.
No.
Take it, snake!
Take it!
Uh!
Go, snake!
All right!
Come on, wiley!
You hockey warrior!
Hockey Nintendo!
Come on, Jack!
Someone
got lucky, huh?
Think so, blane?
With those lowlife
losers, yeah.
I worry about
your self-esteem,
always losing,
losing, losing.
But you
get used to it.
Want to talk
or play hockey?
First one to three
wins, blane.
Come on, wiley!
Kick that preppy Booty!
You're dead!
You sure are popular.
A little
too popular.
Those girls
are going to
get me killed.
Killed?
See that guy--number 2?
His name's Jack.
That girl's
his girlfriend.
Only don't tell
her that,
because she don't
act like it.
You're afraid?
Nah. I've known
millions of guys
like him.
The more they yell,
the more harmless
they are.
See that look?
It's war.
Central high pride--
got to fight for that.
I don't think
there's anything
worth fighting for.
Nothing?
I once knew
this real badass
who always fought
over waves.
Anyone came near
a wave he was on,
he'd fight them.
Didn't matter
how big the guy was.
Real head case.
Anyway, one day
he comes across
this kid
on a boogie board
who has the nerve
to be on his wave.
He says to himself,
"I'll teach this kid
a lesson."
So he surfs
over to him,
only he gets
too close,
and the skegs
on the board
slice into
the kid's head.
There was blood
everywhere.
Kid nearly drowned.
Was he all right?
Yeah. he's got
this scar
on the side
of his head.
What happened to
the surfer?
He's living
in Cincinnati.
It's funny.
You get so busy
fighting over waves
that you never enjoy
the ocean.
Life's too short
for that.
So what are you into?
The smell
of the ocean,
purple sunsets,
and surfing
in the rain.
You're a poet.
Nah. I just know
what I like.
What you like is nice.
I don't even know
your name.
Nikki.
I'm Mitchell goosen.
Nice to meet you,
Mitchell goosen.
Play hockey.
[Cuckoo-cuckoo]
Great. now we're
a man short.
Fine. we'll play
with five.
I think California here
deserves a shot.
All right.
You're up, surfer.
Nice uniform!
Pass it over here!
Over here!
Come on! Shoot it!
Shoot it!
Aah!
[Buzzer]
Wrong goal!
I didn't know
he's on our team.
Nice shot!
That's
the wrong goal!
I'm sorry, man.
You cost us
the game!
Surfer's got
saltwater in his brain.
That was really good,
what you just did.
That was
really great!
That was fantastic!
Whoa! yay!
God!
All right!
Ha ha ha!
Nice shot.
[Yelling]
Chock-a-block.
Surfer boy,
see you in school.
[Yelling]
Mitchell?
Slash, you dog-dog.
Is that you?
No, it's me--
your cousin wiley.
I thought
you were dead, man.
Are you all right?
You o.K.?
This was
a lot of fun.
Invite me
to the next one.
Here. I'll help you up.
Yeah. ugh...
They're going to kill us.
They don't kill you
for losing hockey games.
You don't know them.
They're mean.
You cost them the game,
Mr. wrong goal.
Yeah, right.
Whatever.
[Irene]
...told me that
she crocheted a cozy
for both the toaster
and the blender.
Hello, boys.
Are you limping?
Oh, lordy lord lord.
What in the name of Buddha
happened to you boys?
Playing hockey, mom.
Hockey? my little wiley
plays hockey?
Did you hear that, Louie?
Did I ever show you
my zamboni
driver-of-the-year award?
Not now, dad!
Father, we have
to buy him a cup.
I got a puck.
No, a cup.
The Stanley cup?
You have to win
something first.
It's good to dream,
isn't it, father?
Oh, I'm feeling
frisky.
Let's get that
twister game out.
Wiley, let go.
We'll be fine.
See? I told you.
Wiley!
Come on.
Nothing is going
to happen to us.
We'll be fine.
Mitchell,
how's it going, babe?
Sorry about yesterday.
There we go.
I told you, man.
Hey. how's it going?
All right.
Buenos dias.
This is so cool.
You were right.
Hey, snake,
buenos digos.
[Laughter]
All right!
Here.
* I'm a stranger here *
* and I just moved
into your town *
* I'm a stranger... *
Mitchell!
* and I just moved
into your town *
[sloshing]
* and because I'm a stranger,
everybody's doggin' me around *
* doggin' me around *
hey. what's happening?
Nikki,
what's shaking?
Moondoggie!
Oh, no.
Here comes trouble.
I don't want you
caught up in this,
so I'm going to jam.
No!
Bye-bye.
Very nice, wiley.
You're almost home free.
Make a left
at the light.
* well,
the train stopped here... *
pretty good, huh?
* but the tracks are
out of line *
* I'm going to pack my bags *
* I'm going to move
on down that line **
ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha!
Hey!
Come back here!
[Sloshing]
Huh!
Don't sneak up on me
like that, wiley.
You're touchy.
I'm being stalked
by trained psychopaths.
Yes, I'm touchy.
At least they didn't
put itching powder
in your jockstrap.
I hope the girls
don't think I had
a chubby all day.
That's not exactly
the mental picture
i need
to make
my day better.
It can't last
forever.
Neither can I, man.
I need traffic,
smog, heat waves,
a decent burrito.
I need the ocean.
I can't take it.
You're losing it.
E.t. didn't want
to go home
more than I do.
Come to the market.
My mom needs pigs' feet.
Not what
i had in mind.
You're wanting some
game hen or something?
Mom's pretty liberal
about cooking.
* I got a banana *
* I got-- **
Mitchell!
Louie, come quick!
It's Mitchell!
Jesus, Mary,
and Joseph!
911. don't let it be
an overdose.
Aunt Irene.
Oh, god!
Oh, honey!
Don't you ever do that
to your uncle Louie again!
I was just resting.
We thought
you were on drugs.
No. I'm just tired.
Are you sick?
No. I had
a rough day.
We got a card
from your folks.
Your dad has poison oak,
and you have a package
on your bed.
What is it?
Something
i shouldn't have
forgotten!
Nikki!
Are you o.K.?
How are you?
I'm fine.
Um, just a little spill.
No big deal.
You should
be more careful
on those things.
They're dangerous
if you don't know
what you're doing.
Yeah. I'll be careful
from now on.
What are you doing
right now?
Isn't it pretty?
It's like another world.
It is.
Kind of my ocean.
I want to show you
my favorite flowers.
This one is
my absolute favorite.
Ah, peace Lily.
Beautiful.
Get out. You know
the peace Lily?
You think I live
on a surfboard?
Yeah.
You're right,
but my parents
are encyclopedias.
Well, then,
let's see...
Oh! this one.
Hmm...
Cleopatra's
earrings?
Impressive.
You'll never get
this one. Come here.
This one right here.
What are you doing?
Um, ginger.
Very good.
Loves the water.
My kind of flower.
Thanks.
This one's a gimme.
You'll get this one.
Right here.
Mitchell!
[Bird cawing]
[Cawing]
Mitchell!
Beep-beep!
Ha ha! Got you!
* good, baby, yeah *
* woo, woo, woo,
yeah *
hey!
Can't pass this up!
It's too perfect!
We'll get kicked out.
* ...Tell me what you want,
baby *
* I'll give you
more than you need *
whoa! ha ha!
Hey! wait up!
* show me what it takes *
* for you to notice me *
* whoa, whoa *
* if I picked you up
in my personal limousine *
* and showered you with roses *
* I would wine and dine you
like I have a mind to *
* if that's what it takes *
* to prove, baby *
* my love is good enough *
* whoo *
* good enough place to start **
you are so crazy.
You were the first
smiling face I've seen
in three weeks.
Thank you.
Have you ever been
to huntington beach?
I've never been
to the beach.
You've got to
get to L.A.
And watch
the sunset.
You must be homesick.
Not right now.
Young man,
can I see you a second?
I had a really
good time today.
We can do this again.
I know this great
restaurant.
We could have a good time.
Sounds good.
How about Friday?
O.k.
That's my bus.
Oh, I'm supposed to
go out on the town
with wiley
Friday night.
Bring him along.
I don't know
if he's got a date.
I'll bring a friend.
Cool.
O.k., well, good-bye,
Mitchell goosen.
I think I'm starting
to like Cincinnati!
Cool.
Whoa!
Oh!
Oh, cool!
All right! Go!
Yeah!
All right!
Hey! hey!
How's my long-lost
cousin doing?
What are you
happy about?
It's called amore, bro.
You're wasting water.
What's her name?
Nikki--
and we have a date
Friday night.
We're going out
I got you one, too.
You did what?
You got me a date?
She better be a babe
if you want me
to say yes!
I get
dozens of offers
for Friday night.
She better have
nice eyes and teeth.
South bay, South Africa.
No one around.
No cameras. No sponsors.
Just the goose
and the wave.
And a sweet wave it is.
6...no, 7-foot.
Point break right.
Spittin' like
a washing machine.
An awesome ride.
Even more awesome because
he's in Cincinnati.
Yes, Cincinnati.
Never been done before.
Mitchell!
Hey, Mitchell!
[Radio playing]
Do you think Gloria would go for
the alienated, misunderstood,
kind of walking-on-the-fringe-
of-society kind of look?
Isn't that
what you wear every day?
Yeah.
All right.
Mr. smart guy, Mr. gq,
help me
pick something out.
Let's see what you got.
* I'm too sexy for my love *
* too sexy for my love *
* love's going to leave me *
ha ha ha!
* I'm too sexy for my shirt *
* too sexy
for my shirt *
* so sexy it hurts *
* and I'm too sexy for Milan *
* too sexy for Milan,
New York, and Japan *
* I'm too sexy for your party *
* too sexy for
your party *
* no way I'm disco dancing *
* I'm a model,
you know what I mean? *
* and I do my little turn
on the catwalk *
* yeah, on the catwalk *
* on the catwalk, yeah *
* I do my little turn
on the catwalk **
you are not
my cousin.
Come on. I give up.
Popeye was a great man.
Do you know why?
Never joined
the hair club for men?
Because his motto was
"i am what I am."
Popeye never worried
about what he wore
just to get olive oyl
in the sack.
Do you know why?
He was gay?
Because he is
what he is.
Hmm...
Hello. uh...Uh,
g-Gloria, I'm wiley.
This is--how you doing?
Um, I can drive.
[Cough]
Let's go
to the waterfront
before
we hit shadows.
Sounds like a plan.
I just got
my driver's
license.
That's nice.
Only took him
three times.
Ha ha ha!
Well,
just hop in.
Here you go.
[Engine starts]
Aah!
[Crash]
[Car alarm sounding]
[Tires squealing]
The car works fine.
If you could have lunch
with any three people
alive, dead,
fictitious--
I don't care--
who would it be?
What kind
of a question is that?
It's a fun one.
Come on.
I'd have
to say Tom curren,
greatest surfer alive.
And, um, maybe Gandhi--
not for lunch, though.
He wouldn't eat much.
And the third one?
I'd have to say you.
Me?
You could have lunch
with anyone,
and you'd choose me?
You're not just anyone.
You're special.
* try my love, baby *
* yeah, yeah *
* try *
* try my love *
* my love *
* try my love... *
so...do you come
to the pier a lot?
Oh, yeah. It has
a beautiful atmosphere,
although personally--
because the best side
of the pier is down there.
You got to--
[coughing]
Hungry?
Starving.
Yeah, great.
* all you have to do
is try **
uh, guys.
Hey, can we go,
because Gloria's
hungry?
Ravenous.
I really think
she likes me, man.
Besides, she knows
all the lyrics
to "you ate my train"
by jennie youngman.
I don't know teachers
that boring...
Or weird.
He's just
a little nervous.
He's nervous?
He came 2 inches
from slamming into
a gas truck.
It was like something
out of red asphalt.
He'll grow on you.
Not in this lifetime.
My dad shot her.
It was weird.
Didn't i
tell you guys
this was fun?
I love this place.
I practically live here.
They're going
to set me up a cot.
Oh, that's funny.
I've never seen you
around here before.
I come on Tuesdays.
Yeah,
i sit in the back.
I come in
very late...
Very late.
Hey, you don't mind
if Walt and I join you?
Blane,
get out of here.
Nikki's got herself
a new little friend.
Dude, this is a private
thing we've got.
You understand.
Why don't
we get together
some other time
and go bowling?
Ha ha ha!
Yeah,
i like bowling,
but I don't want
to leave, blane.
Leave? before we can thank
our star hockey player?
Why, that would be rude.
I understand
what you're saying.
Thanks, and good-bye.
[Gloria]
do something.
Leave us alone, huh?
Let's get out of here.
Good idea.
Pardoned at last.
Ow! let go of me,
blane.
Be cool.
There is no reason
to start anything.
Shut up.
We're dancing.
Look, just leave her
alone, all right?
Come on.
Just back off, huh?
Leave her alone,
dude.
I beg your pardon.
What did you say?
You heard me,
blane.
Ow.
[Gloria]
blane.
Come here.
Don't you miss me?
Mitchell.
Hey!
Let her go!
Get lost. This has
nothing to do with you.
Stay away
from my sister.
I'm not
telling you again.
Let her decide
for herself.
She already did.
Get out of here!
This isn't over,
Jack.
Hey, you all right?
Yeah...i'm fine.
All right. Come on.
I'll give you a ride.
I don't need one.
I'm here with...
Ha ha ha!
Yeah, right.
The maharajah's
your date.
Jack, this is no
concern of yours.
Let's talk
about this over
a basket of fries.
Let's take
that basket of fries
and shove them
down your throat.
Come on, man. Chill.
I'm taking you home,
Nikki.
Stop acting
like a cave man.
I'm here with Mitchell.
I'll have her home early...
Sometime before dawn.
Is everything with you
always a joke?
Are you always
serious?
She'll be fine.
Loosen your jocks
a little.
I'm taking Nikki home.
There's nothing
you can do about it.
You understand me,
surfer boy?
Do you think
I'm an idiot?
You've been doing this
for three weeks now--
trying to suck me
into your game.
I'm not going
to fight you, Jack.
He's afraid, Jack.
He's not afraid
of anything.
Is that right?
Is that right, man?
You afraid?
You afraid of me?
You think calling me
a few names,
putting sand in my locker
will make me fight you?
Well, you got
another thing coming.
I don't care about you,
your school,
or your hockey game.
I'm gone in three months.
You think I'm wasting
time on you or anyone?
You ain't worth it.
No one here is--no one.
Nikki!
Gloria,
you want a lift?
I guess so.
Wait up, dude.
Aw, just stop with
the dude stuff, man.
I thought surfers were
supposed to be tough.
I should have
fought them all?
Yeah.
Yeah, something.
It would have
been better.
You didn't do
anything.
What would it have solved?
Nothing. I know.
What about Nikki?
You just let her go.
Let her go?
She walked away from me.
You didn't tell me
she was Jack's sister.
I didn't know.
Doesn't matter.
What's the point?
I'm gone soon.
You really
disappoint me, man.
Wiley.
[Mitchell]
Nikki.
I need to speak
to you.
Don't bother.
It doesn't matter.
You never gave me
a chance.
You're leaving soon.
It's not worth the hassle.
That's not
what I meant.
Don't bother.
It's not worth the hassle.
* ...Wants to say it *
* amen *
* I've got to let you know
for worse or for better *
* there's a hundred ways
that I could show you *
* but it wouldn't matter *
* it's time to tell you,
and I'll try to keep it simple *
* I know what you want to hear *
* why do I forget
every time you get near? *
* you're right on the tip
of my tongue *
* right on the tip
* my tongue *
of my tongue *
* on the tip of my tongue *
* look in my eyes
and tell me what do you see *
* there's a message
that I'm sending *
* I hope you receive *
* words get tangled up
in good intentions *
* I know what my heart
wants to say **
wiley, wake up, man.
I have to tell you something.
Get up. Get up.
I had this dream.
There was this wave,
and it was not
this gidget fart wave.
It was the big mugamba--
the one,
the solar eclipse wave.
I was riding it, dude--
styling big-time--
until I see this
mondo shark--
made jaws
look like a guppy.
His name was pepe.
Pepe. and he starts
coming my way,
but then he stops
and looks me in the eye.
He says--
in Spanish, no less--
la ola es Mia.
I spoke Spanish
in my dream
because I knew it.
"The wave is mine."
The wave is mine.
Then I woke up.
You woke me because
of a lousy dream?
Everything we need to know
is in our dreams.
They're windows
to enlightenment.
So...what did
this shark--pepe?
Yeah.
What did pepe
tell you?
Well, it's obvious
that Jack is the shark
and Nikki's the wave,
and he doesn't want me
near his sister.
La ola es Mia.
The wave is mine.
So what does he do?
He comes at me like a shark.
He's trying to scare me
from the wave, man.
The point is?
The point is,
when you got
a perfect anything,
you go for it.
You ignore the shark.
There are always sharks,
but how often does this
perfect wave come along?
So you'll fight Jack?
And have Gandhi
roll over in his grave?
I don't think so.
Besides...
You don't have
to fight the shark
to get the wave.
Aah!
[Crash]
Come on, wiley.
Hold on.
I'm coming.
Don't stop.
Go on ahead. I'm fine.
Yeah, thanks for asking.
Hey, what's he doing here?
Can we talk?
No.
Then what's
a good time?
After the game,
then.
After the game.
Jack.
Jack, does he
think he'll play?
I don't know
what he thinks,
but he'd better
leave.
Let the moron play.
What for?
That way, we can
kick his butt.
Hey, yeah!
You got room for another?
Travis, you're off.
Adios,
California boy.
Uh, you guys
have a stick?
Whoo!
Don't stop here,
moondoggie.
Go get them, surfer.
Yes.
That was
pretty good.
Nikki, wait.
Go after him,
Mitchell.
Come on, man.
Get him, man.
Come on. Let's go.
Come on.
Just punch him, man.
We're here.
Let's do it.
Come on, you little wimp.
Come on.
Do it.
You think
he'll cry,
blane?
Ha ha ha!
Come on.
Hit me.
I want to see
if he'll cry.
I feel a tear
coming on.
Ha ha ha!
What's wrong with you?
Why didn't you do anything?
Why did you
back down again?
Mitchell. hello...
Mitchell.
Mitchell!
Shut up!
Full-on mooner!
Time to change
your underwear, eh, blane?
Chocolate stain,
blane?
Funny!
Get him.
Get that little wimp.
You were right.
There are some things
worth fighting for.
Would you go?
Not till you let me
tell you about my dream.
Go!
The cars!
Move the cars.
Move the cars!
The cars!
Hey, do you guys
have the right house?
Yeah.
is Mitchell home?
Yeah, sure.
Um, come on in, guys.
Uh, su casa es mi casa,
snake.
Augie, Mark--
Tony, man.
What's up,
rosenblat?
You must be wiley's
little friends.
Look, father--
wiley's little friends.
Yeah. hi.
Wiley talks about
you all the time.
Would you boys like
some grape kool-aid?
Um...
No. no, thank you,
ma'am.
Well, then, uh...
Father, let's make
some caramel corn.
Yeah. I'm watching the, uh--
come on, and don't burn
the oleo this time.
All right.
Mitchell, uh...
These guys
came to see you.
Guys.
Hey! hey!
That was some
piece of skating
today, Mitchell.
I never laughed
so hard.
I guess we just
figured you all wrong.
Shoot, man,
I'm really sorry.
It's all right.
It's over.
All right.
Cool, man.
This is the story.
We've been challenged
by the preps
to a skating race.
We're settling this thing.
You know, I wanted--
we thought maybe
you'd want to come
and skate on our team.
Help us out.
What do you say?
Where's
the race?
Devil's backbone.
Uh...
[Coughing]
We'd have
a better chance
with you.
What's
devil's backbone?
Only the most dangerous hill
in the whole town.
The last guy
who walked down that hill
got so messed up,
forgot who he was...
Pins in his head.
It's a bunch of hills.
It's pretty dangerous.
Then why do this?
We're always being
put down.
Treated like trash.
We're somebody.
It's our chance
to prove it.
We can only
do it as a team.
Are you in?
[Wiley]
all this because of
a shark named pepe?
What are you doing?
Getting ready to shred.
Oh, wiley, no.
I know. I know.
Jack!
The rules are
there are no rules.
Anything goes.
Why don't we
start the race?
[Mimicking]
let's just
start the race.
The first team
with three over the line wins!
Racers set!
Whoo!
Cool it, blane!
Knock it off!
Get off me!
Ugh!
[Horn honking]
Get off me!
Hang on!
Yeah!
Oh! no!
Aah!
Ugh!
Ahh...
[Skate brakes squealing]
[Horns honking]
[Horn honking]
Ah ah ah ah!
Trees!
[Horns honking]
Oh!
Aah!
Come on, Mitchell!
Catch up!
Grab on!
Don't fall, man!
[Horn honks]
[Horn honking]
[Panting]
Icon posos!
Where'd they go?
Yeah!
Yay!
Man, that guy's fast.
We're ahead
two to one now.
They get one more prep in,
they win!
Come on, Jack.
We got
a race to win.
Let's do it.
Thank you.
Did we win?
Yay!
Waa!
Ugh!
I'm o.K.
Now--popeye...
There was
a great man.
What a guy.
Hey!
Captioning performed by
the national captioning
institute, inc.
Captions copyright 1993
icon distribution, inc.
Public performance of captions
prohibited without permission of
national captioning institute
* whoa, whoa *
* yeah *
* good, baby, yeah *
* woo whoo woo, yeah *
* my love is good enough *
* won't you tell me
what you want, baby? *
* I'll give you
more than you need *
* hey *
* won't you show me
what it takes *
* for you to notice me? *
* whoa, whoa *
* if I picked you up
in my personal limousine *
* and showered you with roses *
* I would wine and dine you
like I have a mind to *
* if that's what it takes
to prove, baby *
* my love is good enough *
* whoo *
* good enough place to start *
* whoa, my love is good enough *
* good enough
to open your heart *
* to me *
* won't you show me
what you like, baby? *
* I only want to please you *
* and I'm not really begging,
baby *
* you've got me on my knees *
* oh, you know it *
* I would do anything you say *
* any little thing at all *
* if I told you I'd wait
no matter how long it takes *
* would that make you believe,
baby? *
* oh *
* my love is good enough *
* yeah *
* good enough place to start *
* oh-oh *
* my love is good enough *
* good enough to open
your heart *
* my love is good enough *
* oh, baby *
* don't you think
it's worth a try? *
* my love is good enough *
* yeah *
* good enough for you and I *
* come on over, baby *
* my love is good enough *
* yeah *
* good enough *
* you know it, baby *
* oh *
* yeah *
* come on *
* ow *
* hey *
* yeah *
* if that's what it takes
to prove, baby *
* my love is good enough *
* yeah *
* good enough place to start *
* my love is good enough *
* come on, baby *
* good enough
to open your heart **